SRUJANA KALYADAPU

Lafayette, IN | 765-694-5240 | skalyada@purdue.edu | srujana-kalyadapu

PROFILE

Graduate student in Business Analytics and Information Management seeking full-time roles in consulting, data analytics and supply chain analytics with 3 years of experience in managerial and analytical roles in supply chain, consumer goods and consultancy.

Technical Skills: Python, SOL, R, Microsoft Excel | Visualization Tools: PowerBI, Tableau

Statistical Tools: Machine learning, Data Mining, Statistical Modeling

EDUCATION

Purdue University, Daniels School of Business

Master of Science in Business Analytics and Information Management

West Lafayette, IN August 2024

National Institute of Technology, Warangal Bachelor of Technology, Chemical Engineering Warangal, Telangana August 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Microsoft

Data Scientist

West Lafayette, Indiana January 2024 – April 2024

- Collaborated on the Microsoft AI Cloud Pipeline's project to improve product information quality on Meijer's site, aiming to enhance customer satisfaction and reduce attrition.
- Actively engaged in developing an automated product description framework using image recognition and language models to ensure consistency in Meijer's product listings.

Merilytics

Hyderabad, India

Senior Business Associate

February 2023 – July 2023

- Guided a team to design and construct interactive dashboards for Inventory, Marketing, and Customer Analytics, serving a prominent US-based health and wellness product client.
- Developed a comprehensive model inventory model that tracked flow of inventory from firm's establishment in 2018 until June 2023
- Provided valuable insights on newly launched product performance tracking and assessed potential cannibalization effects for the client.
- Achieved a significant 50% reduction in variance for products contributing to 80% of revenue, substantially enhancing demand forecasting efficiency.

Hindustan Unilever Limited

Mumbai, India

Assistant Availability and Kitting Manager – Supply Chain, Customer Success

August 2020 - November 2022

- Developed dashboards and reports in customer success, facilitating smooth merger of the nutrition business of GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) with Hindustan Unilever Limited (HUL).
- Implemented warehouse replenishment strategies in a dynamic Modern Trade wing of an FMCG company delivering more than 3000 products to nearly 2000 customer delivery points.
- Led planning and execution of repackaging operations for multiple consumer specific product promotions at 3 sites, ensured on-time and in-full delivery amounting to zero business loss.
- Recognized for ensuring stock availability for two highest-valued customers, resulting in approximately 30% customer business growth.

PROJECTS

Delivery Operations Optimization at STEM Store: SQL, Tableau

• Enhanced STEM Store's delivery operations with dynamic vendor allocation, reducing lead time by 40% and shipment costs by 15%, driving customer satisfaction and business growth.

NLP Classification: Misuse of the Craigslist Platform | Python, Transformers

• Designed and implemented text analysis model for Craigslist, integrating BERT and GloVe ML algorithms to achieve 90% accuracy in identifying and flagging inappropriate content, enhancing platform moderation.

Enhancing Bankruptcy Prediction: A Data-Driven Approach to Financial Risk Assessment | Python, SaaS, ML models

• Formulated a predictive model for bankruptcy likelihood using financial ratios, employing Gradient Boosting, HP Neural, and Logistic Regression models to achieve AUC of 0.935, enhancing decision-making and risk assessment.

CERTIFICATIONS

 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900) | AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner | Tableau Desktop Specialist | Operations Research with SAS Optimization | Google Advanced Data Analytics (Coursera) | Associate Data Scientist in Python (datacamp) | SQL Server Developer (datacamp)